A Guide to the American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) records FA079
Rockefeller Archive Center
- American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) photographs, 1946-1968, n.d.; 1027; 6.2 Cubic Feet 19 boxes.
  - General, 1
    - Programa Interamericano para la Juventud Rural (PIJR), (Inter-American Rural Youth Program), General, Prints: 48 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      18. Girls of Pimpinela learned how to preserve fruits and vegetables with CBR's technical assistance. 19. Participants at Inter-American Rural Youth Leaders' Conference. 20. The Inter-American Rural Youth Technical Committee in Rio de Janeiro. 21. 4-S Club member demonstrates Fruit Tree Grafting during the VI National 4-S Club Encampment. 22. 4-S member demonstrates on nutrition. 23. Pauline E. Wallace, Club member from Jamaica, presents demonstration on sewing. 24. Rupert A. Gordon, Club member from Jamaica, shows how to make a lamp. 25. Berta Morales, 5-V Club member from Venezuela, presents demonstration during Congress in Panama. 26. Lupe Gisela Jaen, 4-S club member from Panama, presents demonstration. 27. Here we see a 5-V club member of Pimpinela giving a demonstration on how to remove honey from a bee panel. 28. Club members, F. Cebelloa, Josefina Esparragoza and technicians from the agricultural extension agency at Villa de Cura, Aragua State, Venezuela. Corn production contest. 29. Rafael Pimental with his plot after it had been planted for 69 days. Corn production contest, Venezuela. 30. Extension agent supervises 4-S club member corn project. Iztapaluca, Mexico. 31. Corn production project of 4-S member, Ofelia de Leon. (H-125 corn and use of irrigation) Iztapaluca, Mexico. 32. Southern zone coordinator presents PIJR plaque to International Minerals & Chemical Cooperation in their headquarters in Skokie, Il. 33. Dra. Linda Nelson, special guest to the closing ceremony of the V 4-A Clubs National Convention, present PIJR awards and recognitions. Buenos Aires, Argentina, Nov. 18, 1966. 34. Mr. Roy F. Hebard, Public Relations Director of the Sears Roebuck Foundation of Chicago and Sr. J V Ruy Barbosa, Public Relations Director of Sears of Brasil S/A visit CNC-4S to discuss Sears Heifer Project $1,000 donation which will be used for community development 4-S project, medals, trophies, and trips to Convention and Congress. 35. No caption. 36. Group of participants at the 1st Inter-American Seminar for Executive Secretaries of Rural Youth Program Support Entities. 37. Seminar participants at Conference table. 38. PIJR Director presented with "Partner in 4-H National Citation" by Administrator of USA Federal Extension Service at the Dept of Agriculture Auditorium. In the background are: Miss Sandra Olsen and Mr. Peter Lorenz, Mr. Law's Conference sponsors. 39. Response for receiving the award. 40. President of Panama addresses inaugural session of Congress which was broadcasted by "Radio Union de Panama". 41. Ing. Fernando Suarez de Castro during his conference on Rural Youth Participation in Agrarian Reform Program. 42. CADA representative hands Bs. 40.000 to Evelio Tovar of the Venezuelan 5-V club Association. 43. Mr. Johyn C. Goulden, Director of Ford motor do Brasil, SA visits the National 4-S Club Committee to present Ford's donation of Cr. 2.800.000 (Cruzeiros) to sponsor the achievement project. 44. Representatives of IRETAMA - Fertilizer Company - Rio de Janiero agreement of Cr. 1.000.000 to sponsor trips to Convention and Congress. 45. Mr. WA Johns of the Singer Sewing Machine Company of Sao Paulo, Brasil presents their contribution to Oswaldo Silva, National 4-S Club Committee Vice- Secretary to sponsor the national clothing project. 46. Director and Executive Secretary of the National 4-S club Committee, and Esso Brasileira de Petrolo SA in Rio de Janiero to sign a Cr. 2.500.000 agreement. This donation is to furnish awards to the leadership project winners at municipal, state and national levels. Left to right: Paulo Barbosa, Vice- President of Esso; Geraldo O. D. Machado, II Vice-President of CNC-4S; Francisco de Castro neves, I Vice-Pres of CNC-4-S; Mario Torres de Melo, Director of Public Relations of Esso; Athanael Martins da Fonesca, Executive Secretary of CNC-4S and Mauilio Silva, Manager of Public Relations of Esso. 47. 1966 IFYE participants. 48. 1966 IFYE work groups 49. 1966 IFYE work groups 50. A new agreement in which AIA passed the direction of PIJR to the National 4-H Club Foundation of the US was signed in San Jose, the 13th of December, 1967. From left to right: Howard E. Law, Dir. Of PIJR; Grant Shrum, Dir. Nat. 4-H Club Foundation; Armando Samper, Dir. Gen of IICA and John R. Camp, Executive VP of AIA. 51. PIJR Director talks at the inauguration of vocational school sponsored by the "Colegio de Contadores", Asuncion, Paraguay. 1966 52. Members of Guatemalan delegation observe demonstration on how to make cement blocks, Tambor, Alajuela, Costa Rica. 1964 53. Mr. Lawrence Levy, Treasurer and Mrs. Flor P. Brennan, Secretary of AIA visit 4-S club member home to observe their projects. 1965 54. Mr. James Hyde, Rockefeller Brothers Fund Representative Visited 4-S Club Projects in Costa Rica. 1962 55. 4-C Club National Winners give demonstration on cutting up a chicken for which they were awarded an exchange trip to Mexico. 1963 56. Oscar Godinez, 4-S Club Member from Guatemala shows President of El Salvador how to Vaccinate Baby Chickens. 1963 57. Dinner and meeting at which National 4-F Club Foundation of Ecuador was established. 1967 58. Edgar Arias, Rural Youth Program Assistant, gives talk and leads discussion on "giving" and "judging" 4-S club demonstration 59. Edgar Arias, Rural Youth Program Assistant, gives talk and leads discussion on "giving" and "judging" 4-S club demonstration 60. - 65. No caption.
    - Programa Interamericano para la Juventud Rural (PIJR), (Inter-American Rural Youth Program), Leader's Conference, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1966; Prints: 7 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      66. - 72. No caption.
    - Reports, AIA 1960 Progress Report, Prints: 50 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      1. Modernization, technical guidance and commercialism of farm production should be the basic objective of farm policy. 2. Modernization, technical guidance and commercialism of farm production should be the basic objective of farm policy. 3. Farm Credit and Savings facilities should be extended to many more strategically located towns and villages. 4. Supervised credit - to train and guide the farm families toward improved farm and home management techniques while extending credit in the right amounts and under such terms as will make improved methods possible. 5. Supervised credit - to train and guide the farm families toward improved farm and home management techniques while extending credit in the right amounts and under such terms as will make improved methods possible. 6. CVF sponsored projects have brought about spectacular increases in the production of rice, sugar and other important agricultural commodities. 7. CVF sponsored projects have brought about spectacular increases in the production of rice, sugar and other important agricultural commodities. 8. The production methods used in most Venezuelan farms are labor consuming, inefficient and often times primitive. 9. The production methods used in most Venezuelan farms are labor consuming, inefficient and often times primitive. 10. Most of the farmers of Venezuela operate small units. Approximately 85% of them have farms which average slightly more than 7 hectares in size. 11. Most of the farmers of Venezuela operate small units. Approximately 85% of them have farms which average slightly more than 7 hectares in size. 12. Men seeking mere subsistence have laid bare with fire and machete forest lands unfit for agricultural purposes, leaving behind them extensive areas of despoiled land. 13. Men seeking mere subsistence have laid bare with fire and machete forest lands unfit for agricultural purposes, leaving behind them extensive areas of despoiled land. 14. The Banco Agricola y Pecuario has survived many crises and performed functions without which the agricultural health of the nation would have suffered. 15. For training purposes a wide variety of methods and techniques should be used. 16. Through the use of credit farmers are enabled to improve their herds and modernize their production methods. 17. Through the use of credit farmers are enabled to improve their herds and modernize their production methods. 18. The people of Venezuela have inherited a land whose earth holds incalculable riches. 19. The people of Venezuela have inherited a land whose earth holds incalculable riches. 20. Technical guidance and modern farming methods on IAN colonies such as Turen are helping to solve the acute food problems in Venezuela. 21. Venezuela must solve the conuquero problem and eliminate antiquated production methods. 22. Venezuela must solve the conuquero problem and eliminate antiquated production methods. 23. Farm credit is an effective tool in an agricultural policy designed to improve conditions and further agricultural development. 24. Farm credit is an effective tool in an agricultural policy designed to improve conditions and further agricultural development. 25. - 50. No caption.
    - Reports, AIA 1960 Progress Report, Prints: 46 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      51. Information Program. 52. No caption. 53. No caption. 54. Mauricio Ramira[illegible] 55. No caption. 56. Progress Report to Trustees, October 56-57 57. No caption. 58. No caption. 59. No caption. 60. The corn plants in foreground show zinc deficiency. They received the same treatment as those in the background minus zinc. Anapolis experiment, Jan 1959. 61. Progress Report to Trustees, June 1959. 62. A Nicaraguan, Panamanian, Columbian, Costa Rican, and Brazilian work on a group involvement problem in communications during the "Train-the-Trainer" course given in Costa Rica. 63. No caption. 64. Radio interview techniques being practiced in the field. 65. Audio-visual training center, Torrialba, Costa Rica. 66. Learning various printing processes makes the information specialist more versatile. 67. In service motion picture production training. 68. Interview techniques in news writing are stressed. 69. The elements of slide film and motion picture script writing are taught. 70. Learning printing processes by actually taking part in their operation. 71. Participant team working on a communications problem in the "Train-the-Trainer" course given in Costa Rica. 72. Interview techniques are taught to improve reporting abilities. 73. First-hand experience in newspaper operations is important to making the most effective use of the medium. 74. First-hand experience in newspaper operations is important to the thorough understanding of the use of this medium of communications. 75. Radio interview techniques being studied in the field. 76. Getting to understand the editorial phase at newspaper composition and writing. 77. Learning radio broadcasting techniques. 78. (Radio interview techniques.) Students are taught to write, produce, and deliver their own radio programs. 79. An Ecuadorian and Brazilian work on a communications problem in the "Train-the-Trainer" course given in Costa Rica. (There is nothing like a pretty face to illuminate a report, I always say.) 80. Seed selection - A CBR technician showing farmers how to select a better corn. 81. The communications center at Torrialba, Costa Rica. 82. No caption. 83. No caption. 84. No caption. 85. No caption. 86. No caption. 87. Drink Milk for Health - a glass of milk for pre-school age children as served in CBR rural community center. Centers are run by local volunteers with CBR guidance. 88. Teaching effective writing for all media is backbone of course. 89. No caption. 90. Learning radio broadcasting techniques - another example of on-the-spot type of training. 91. Dr. Tiburcio LInares, PAAP veterinarian, examines a Jersey calf before giving it some medicine orally. 4/1960 92. No caption. 93. Girl and boy members of 4-S Clubs (which correspond to American 4-H Clubs) gather at a state convention. ACAR. 94. No caption. 95. Better Nutrition - Showering home management technicians how to put on a demonstration of food preparation for farm women under CBR guidance. 96. No caption.
    - Reports, AIA 1962 Progress Report, Prints: 70 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      1. - 70. No caption.
    - Reports, AIA Training Program, Caracas, Venezuela, Prints: 12 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      1. Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences at Turrialba, Costa Rica, where AIA, in cooperation with the Ministry of Agriculture, sends Venezuelan youths under scholarships to be trained in practical farming and rural leadership. 2. Venezuelan students attend class in rural reconstruction at Institute. AIA's training program provides for 300 one-year scholarships over a 10 year period to prepare farm youths to contribute to the improvement of rural Venezuela. 3. Students learn by working daily in the fields and gardens where emphasis is given to soil preparation, seed selection, fertilization, pest control, and planting, harvesting, storage and marketing of crops. 4. The Institute's fields, pastures, stables, orchards, gardens, shops and rural demonstration center cover 1,100 hectares. Trainees are paid for their work on demonstration fields to cover their personal expenses. 5. Lesson in coffee growing. Besides actual crop cultivation, trainees study labor problems, machinery, agricultural economics, farm organization and management in preparation for a rile of rural leadership in their communities. 6. Trainees learn art of brick making and construction of rural housing as part of the rural reconstruction course aimed to fit students to assist in the development of isolated farm communities in their home countries. 7. A practical class in beekeeping forms part of the Institute's course in development of small rural industries which mean extra income to farmers. Modern bee hives were built by the students in carpentry classes. 8. Students construct poultry house. Special training is given in poultry husbandry including planning of enterprises, feeding, housing, sanitation, incubation and breeding, diseases and parasite control and marketing of products. 9. Trainees make compost as part of soil technology class; 37 AIA scholarship students have completed the practical farming course at Turrialba in the past three years and are working in agricultural programs throughout Venezuela. 10. Extensive animal husbandry and dairy industry allows ample training of students in all phases of livestock operations including beef and dairy herd management and breeding, and marketing of products. 11. "Turrialba boys" return to Venezuela, many of them to manage their own farms or the farms of others, many to work for the Ministry of Agriculture and its various branches; still others work with CBR in its various farm programs. 12. As a CBR supervised credit agent, this former Turrialba scholar visits with a farm family to work out a plan to utilize the credit (above). Then he goes into the field with the farmer. Here he explains the poor productivity of a papaya.
    - Reports, Pictures Used in 1959 Report, Prints: 29 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      1. - 8. No caption. 9. Note attached to photo: Howard - a better photo has been requested from Brazil. 10. Herbicide and mulch. 11. - 27. No caption. 28. CBR reporter covered major agricultural areas of country for radio interviews, news stories. 29. ACAR - Tres Pontos (Pereira Family).
    - Reports, Pictures Used in 1959 Report (Photomechanicals/Graphs), Prints: 12 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      1. Stilbestrol Experiment. 2. Stilbestrol Experiement. 3. Net profit as related to nitrogen fertilization. 4. Effects of nitrogen on corn yields. 5. Net profit as related to nitrogen fertilization. 6. Height of pangola grass on a "campo" soil. 7. Animal gains or losses during winter. 8. Coffee production, 1954-1957. 9. Effects of nitrogen on corn yields. 10. Effects of nitrogen on grass growth during cool and warm seasons. 11. Payout from nitrogen and Stilbestrol on Coloniao pasture. 12. Animal gains (liveweight) after grazing 112 days.
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Miscellaneous South America Trips, 1951, 1956; Prints: 3 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      1. Rio 1951, Vargas Inauguration. 2. No caption. 3. No caption.
    - Stanley, Dr. Louise, News Pictures - Nutrition, Prints: 6 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      1. Dr. Bertha Lutz, prominent feminine leader in Brazil, with Dr. Louise Stanley and Dr. Afranio Carvalho, Cabinet Chief to the Minister of Agriculture. 2. A convite do Dr. Josue de Castro, Chefe do Instituto de Nutricao no Brasil, a Dra. Louise Stanley, nutricionista norte-americana, dirigiu-se aos membros do Curso do Instituto de Nutricao durante a recente reuniao realisada na Santa Casa de Nisericordia. A palestra da Dra. Stanley sobre como os problemas de nutricao nos Estados Unidos tinham sido encarados e solucionados, despertou grande interesse entre os membres da Faculdade Nacional de Medicina que desenpenham atividades identicas neste paiz. A Dra. Stanley visita o Brasil a convite do Sr. Nelson Rockefeller e sob os auspicious da American International Association for Economic and Social Development (Associao Internacional Americana de Fomento Economico e Socail) a fim de colher inforacoes autoizades sobre a situacao alimentar e dos generos de nutricao no pais. 3. Dr. Louise Stanley and Dr. Josue de Castro, head of the Instituto de Nutricao, exchange a good neighbor handshake. 4. Dr. Louise Stanley, Senator Appolonio Salles and Mr. Kenneth Kado trade jokes at the AIA cocktail party for Dr. Stanley. 5. Sra. Ana Amalia Carneiro de Mendonca de Queirez, founder of the Casa de Estudiante, discusses student cafeteria problems with Dr. Louise Stanley, foremost American nutritionist in Brazil to study that situation at the request of Mr. Nelson Rockefeller. 6. Dr. Louise Stanley with Senator Appolonio Salles and Dr. John Griffing, at the cocktail party given in her honor by AIA, at the Associao Brasileira de Imprensa.
    - Oversize, Series 1, General, 1962 (Box 19)
      Oversize Materials; Film Scripts, "Design for Hemisphere Action," May 1, 1962 (2 copies)
  - Brazil, 2
    Often within the subseries pertaining to a specific country, the folders are broken down further into the country-specific organizations, separated by specific region within the country (for example, Folder 172 is within Subseries 4, Venezuela, and is entitled "CBR [the specific organization], Barinas [the specific state of Venezuela], Crafts [the specific topic of the photographs]").
    - ACAR, ACAR Annual Report Photographs, 1956; Prints: 22 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      1. - 22. No caption.
    - ACAR, Administration, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Visit to Brazil, May 1956, Prints: 3 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      1. No caption. 2. No caption. 3. No caption.
    - ACAR, Curvelo, Agriculture, Prints: 3 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      1. Farm children meet with ACAR agronomist Erwin Fuchs in hybrid corn fields which they are cultivating as 4-S club project. 2. Curvelo experiment at the left: only lime was applied - at right both lime and phosphate. 3. Curvelo ACAR experiment. This arrow shows the best that can be obtained even with a lime and phosphate treatment (alfalfa).
    - ACAR, DEAD, Prints: 16 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      1. No caption. 2. No caption. 3. Mr. Hudgens and Dr. Carlos Tavares congratulating each other on the successful completion of the first ACAR loan. 4. Group picture of AIA, Caixa Economia and ACAR officials and employees who witnessed the signing of the first loan agreement in Minas Gerais. 10/18/49. 5. Dr. Paulo de Salvo, President of ACAR, speaking at the occasion of the signing of the first loan agreement between ACAR and the Caixa Economica. 10/18/49. 6. Various officials of the Caixa Economica and ACAR witnessing the signing of the first loan agreement by Sra. Sebastiao Onofre da Silveira. 10/18/49. 7. No caption. 8. No caption. 9. Group picture of AIA, Caixa Economica and ACAR officials and employees who witnesses the signing of the first loan agreement in Minas Gerais. 10/18/49. 10. Sebastiao Onofre da Silveira in the act of signing the first loan agreement in the Supervised Credit Plan developed by the Caixa Economica and ACAR. 10/18/49. 11. - 16. Copies of photographs taken at signing of AIA-State Agreement and ACAR-Caixa agreement in Palacio de Liberdade on 27th of December 1951. (note attached)
    - ACAR, Eloi Mendes, Agriculture, Prints: 3 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      1. Spraying pastures for chemical weed control. Agronomist Zalder Araujo of the Associacao de Credito e Assistencia Rural (ACAR) demonstrates to cattle farmer Joao Bemardez and son how to use the new sprayer purchased from loan funds under the supervised credit programs. 2. Agronomist for the Associacao de Credito e Assistencia Rural at Eloi Mendes, Minas Gerais, Brazil, shows farmer how to survey field for terracing to control soil erosion. ACAR lends equipment to farmers until they can afford to buy their own. 3. Demonstration by ACAR staff member at Eloi Mendres, Minas Gerais. ACAR urges farmers to spray and vaccinate cattle, improve pastures and provide supplementary feed which help raise production.
    - ACAR, Itau Community Program, Administration, Prints: 4 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      1. Directors of Companhia Itau and ACAR technicians. 2. ACAR personnel at lunch. 3. ACAR personnel, including six ACAR trainees and two IFYE's. 4. In the ANCAR central office at Belo Horizonte, Miss Aleta McDowell, head of the ACAR home economics department, explains to ANCAR trainees some of the problems of her section. The trainees are (in clockwise order, starting at left) Jose Torres de Menezes, Armando Carneiro da Rocha Filho.
    - ACAR, Itau Community Program, Agriculture, Prints: 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      5. No caption. 6. Dr. Penha of Instituto Biologico works with AIA in helping to control animal disease. These pigs with paralysis were sent to his laboratory for study.
    - ACAR, Itau Community Program, Crafts, Prints: 3 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      7. Wives of farm workers and quarries at Fazenda Nova Granja in Minas Gerais, Brazil, take a lesson in laying out a dress pattern from home supervisor Mairana Leite Pinto. Sewing is one of several activities conducted in the ACAR supervised health and education program inaugurated by the farm's management to improve life for its tenant families. 8. Miss Aleta McDowell, US specialist in home economics and head of that section for ACAR in Minas Gerais, makes a regular supervisory visit to the Itau factory's community center where classes are given in nutrition, sewing, child care, gardening and other aids to better living. ACAR supervises the running of the program and trains Brazilian personnel to handle the job; the factory provides buildings and funds. 9. No caption.
    - ACAR, Itau Community Program, Education/Schools, Prints: 8 (Box 3, Folder 40)